Kampla, Uganda

Mobile: +256777245670 Github: nkukehenry Skype: live:henricsanyu

Email: henricsanyu@gmail.com

HENRY NKUKE

CAREER OBJECTIVE

I am a self-motivated and hardworking software developer with a bachelor's degree in computer science and statistics with 5 years of practice. Am so enthusiastic about skills development and project accomplishment. I still seek to acquire more of the most efficient techniques of problem solving and opportunities of participating in crafting change-causing enterprise solutions.

SKILLS & ABILITIES

Operating Systems: Windows, Windows-Server, MAC, Linux variants. **Programming languages & frameworks**: Java, PHP, HTML, Angular, C#, Android, React js, Lua, Kxml, Kolin, Ionic, CSS and Python

Database and Client/Server Technologies:

MSSQL, MySQL, Apache, Express, Tomcat and MS SQL

Others: Docker, Kubernetes, Git, Apache Camel, Wordpress, Opencart, Code Igniter, MS office, NetBeans, Visual studio, Stata, SPSS, Epidata, Adobe design tools, Laravel, Public Key Infrastructure (PKI), JBOSS fuse, Onsen UI, Flutter, Redis, Docker, etc

Languages: English, Luganda, Runyankole/Rukiga, Kiswahili

KEY PROJECTS

Merchant powered payment system (Yoya Consult Uganda) 2020 - 2021.

(Most recent)

Developed a full payments system with an API backend, REST API and a mobile app. The backend involved integrating to three third party APIs, implementing a merchant wallet system, reporting features, and securely allowing incoming merchant transactions.

Similar solutions (to this) have been implemented for two other clients.

Agency Banking app (Interswitch Uganda) 2018 - 2022.

Led the development of an agency baking app to power Stanbic agency and DFCU agency under Interswitch Uganda. The project including paying attention to merchant user-friendliness, secure transactions, and compliance to strict internal security policies. I also worked on several backend components (at API level) that interact with the app.

I am still responsible for maintaining this project for two high traffic banks.

Agency Banking Integrations (Interswitch Uganda) 2018 - 2022.

Integrated to several bank APIs for agency banking implementations at Interswitch, I was finally assigned responsibility over new implementations and improvements for one of the banks. I have run all changes and improvements for two and a half years now.

Attendance Management solution (Consultant, MoH)

I was responsible for designing scheduling and attendance reporting workflows for this solution as per requirements from ministry of health. This involved writing complex logic to handle and transform data from IHRIS system and build several custom components to suit even the most basic user of the system.

EXPERIENCE

March/2022 - Present: Co-founder & CTO, Splint Investments

Heading development and innovation activities

Solutions design and development

Partner technical Liasson and Systems Integration

Database development and maintenance and monitoring

Application security analysis, enhancement

Aug/2018 – Feb 2022: Application Developer, Interswitch East Africa

Mobile App development (Hybrid & native)

Systems Analysis, design, and development

Enterprise Systems Integration

Database development and maintenance

API development, maintenance, and integrations support (SOAP & RESTFUL)

POS terminal programming

Internal systems development and maintenance

Application security enhancement and evaluation

Dec/2017 – Aug/2018: Freelance IT Support and systems Developer

Mobile App development (Hybrid & native)

Website development and hosting

Systems development and support

General IT support & consultancy

Feb/2016 – Dec/2017: Systems Admin, Megha Industries (U) Ltd

Implemented an internal printer supplies refill system that replaced outsourcing, cutting down printing costs by 70%.

Setting up new workstations.

Performing periodic software and hardware monitoring.

Printer configuration and maintenance.

General network administration (Linux as the core).

User support and training (software and hardware usage guidance)

Systems security analysis

The above tasks were carried out for Six different office locations.

May/2014-Aug/2014

Statistics Internee, Bukomansimbi District Planning Unit

Data Entry, Analysis, and dissemination

May/2013-Aug/2013

Teaching Assistant, Queen of Apostles Academy, Kabale, Uganda

Teaching Mathematics and Computer Literacy to students from S.4 to S.6 Maintaining the computer lab by installing needed software, regulating use and ensuring safety.

Jan/2012-Aug/2012

Librarian, Queen of Apostles Academy, Kabale, Uganda

Took responsibility of managing book circulation, maintaining library cleanliness and accessibility.

Taught Physics and Computer studies to students in S.5 and S.6.

EDUCATION

Institution	Award	Period
Uganda Martyrs University	Bachelor of Science (Computer science and statistics)	2012-2015
Uganda Advanced certificate of education (UACE)	UACE	2010-2011
Uganda certificate of education (UCE)	UCE	2006-2009
Primary Leaving Examinations	PLE	1997-2005

LEADERSHIP

Co-founder, Splint Investments (U) Limited

Period: Feb 2022 April-Present

Responsibilities:

Managing the agent recruitment team.

Partner liaison

Financial projection, planning and monitoring

Product improvement and innovation

Uganda Martyrs University Computer society

President Period: November 2014 – April, 2015

Responsibilities:

Organizing software development, installation and user training sessions (both statistical and generic computing)

Organizing and chairing Computer society meetings, software development committees.

Leading outreach programs to nearby schools.

Uganda Martyrs University Computer Society Legal Advisor

Period: April 2015 – Jan 2016

Responsibilities: Reviewing society plans and providing advice.

REFERENCES

Mr. Denis Kagimu, Interswitch E.A, Head of Applications Dept.

denis.kagimu@interswitchgroup.com / 0706-974-321

Mr. Agaba Andrew, Ministry of Health Systems Developer

+256 702 787688

Mr. Robert Ssebakijje, Yoya Consult

+256 772 095312

Ms. Tiragana Audes, Assistant Registrar, UMU, Nkozi

taudes@gmail.com